What if I told you
that your family was murdered.
Just imagine it for a minute.
Your brothers. sisters.
parents...
your kids...
everyone.
Murdered for no reason at all.
Now ask yourself...
what would you do?
Mom. there's a man outside.
Get your father.
Go now!
Papa. there's a man outside.
Another beggar?
Did he take anything
from the garden?
Max?
Is it you?
Good to see you again.
Ruth and Benjamin.
Did they come back?
Are they here?
Anyone?
Why did you give us away?
The house is mine now.
Where did they take them?
Get off my property!
Just because the war is over
doesn't mean
we can't kill Jews anymore.
The dead give you no rest.
But if you are not among them.
you must have done
something good in your life.
Or something very. very bad.
All dead!
Everyone but not me.
not Avraham.
Can I tell you a secret?
He's right here.
Death. I've captured Death.
I met him in the camp one night.
He was coming for me.
I could hear him
breathing in my ear...
...but he had no idea
who he was dealing with.
I flipped over
as quickly as I could
and trapped him in this sack.
You can still hear him
breathing inside.
And now nobody can kill me!
Shut up. old man!
This used to be our Synagogue.
I got married here.
I had my son's birth here.
We have to get out
of this damned country.
I heard there's a refugee camp
with many Jews at Tarvisio.
From there.
they're sent to Palestina.
the land of Israel.
If your family is still alive.
that's where they'll be.
Come with me.
Stop. stop. stop!
Meat!
Avraham.
Someone is cooking meat!
Avraham. wait!
I told you. I can not die.
Avraham! Wait!
- Wait.
- They have food.
Avraham.
Please!
It's all right.
Hey!
You're fine.
We're the Jewish Brigade.
of the British Army.
No one is going
to hurt you here.
It's all right.
- Give it back.
- No!
Hold on. I'll save you!
Soon we'll get to Tarvisio.
Maybe you'll find news
about your family there.
- Thank you. sir.
- It's Michael.
I'm in charge of these savages.
And that clown over there
is in charge of us.
We are from Palestina.
By the time the Brits
agreed to send us here
the war was almost over.
You see these Brits.
they like their tea
and like to sleep.
And once they do.
we get to do anything we want
right under their noses.
Who did this?
Crazy Jews.
Okay. guys. come on.
let's move fast.
we don't have all day here.
Sir. hey.
Sir. let me help you. come on.
Put your leg here. All right.
Okay.
Listen. sir.
the refugee camp is over there.
Soon you'll be with our brothers
and sisters in Palestina
starting a new life.
I need to find my family first.
My son and my wife.
Ruth and Benjamin.
Can you help me?
Please?
They must be here somewhere.
Maybe we can ask
the British soldiers?
Maybe they have
a list or something?
There is not much I can do.
I'm sorry.
Good luck.
Max. they have beds here!
Real beds!
Look!
There in the tent.
They're good. they're good.
I don't believe it!
Back home. we heard rumors...
about the death camps...
but we didn't believe it
to be true.
We should've done something.
We should have helped you.
But we did nothing.
Put your shoes on.
I want him to see this.
I need you to give us
all the details.
Ranks. addresses.
dates. locations.
Anything?
Please. sir.
I did nothing wrong.
Never killed a man in my life!
Yeah.
- You were just a clerk. right?
- Yes.
- Filling out forms.
- Yes. yes!
Just a clerk.
Give us the names we need.
No.
Ranks. addresses.
dates. locations!
No. you will kill me
once you have them.
It's almost dawn.
We need him
to verify our sources.
Let's finish this.
Please. sir.
Have mercy!
- I have kids.
- How many?
What?
Michael. come on!
Ask him about the kids.
Talk to him about his family.
Okay.
Let's do it quietly and calmly.
Do what we ask
and you'll be fine.
Just give us the information
we need and soon...
you'll see your family again.
How many kids do you have?
Three. but I haven't seen them
for a long time.
I miss them so much.
What are their names?
Franz. Heinrich. Lise.
She's the youngest?
It's okay. look at me.
You'll be fine.
Untie him.
Menash.
Bernhard Peter.
SS Sturmscharführer.
He's hiding
not so far from here.
two buildings
from the town center.
Paul Heller.
It's hope.
If you give someone
the slightest feeling of hope.
they will do anything.
Oberleutnant Arnulf Karl
committed suicide last month.
- That is all I know.
- Very well.
Menash.
Wait!
- Josef Krauss.
- What are you doing?
We find you guilty
for taking part
in participating
in the killings of innocent men.
women and children.
My family. my kids.
Our brothers and sisters.
I did what you asked for.
- I gave you all their names.
- We hereby sentence you to death.
Sir. you promised!
I gave all the names.
you promised!
Thank you.
I wanted you to see this
before you leave.
What are you going to do
with all those names. that list?
There's no list.
Max. there's a convoy
going out tomorrow.
I'll make sure
that you're on it.
Where are they?
Just tell me.
My neighbors.
they locked us in the city hall
for three days.
Your Ruth.
she was there with me.
After three days.
the soldiers came
and took us to the woods.
They forced us to dig.
When we were done.
they lined us up
along the ditch.
When they ran out of bullets.
they used their knives.
After they got tired.
they just buried us alive.
The last time I saw Ruth.
she was hugging Benjamin.
protecting him.
I somehow managed
to escape to the woods.
They told me that the next day.
the ground was still moving.
Some of them were still alive.
but after a while. it stopped.
I'm so sorry.
Come on. sir. come on!
Give me your hand.
Let's do it fast. come on.
Come on. guys.
Let's go. let's do it fast.
What are you waiting for?
Come on!
- I can't.
- What?
This... this soil is cursed.
Soaked in our blood.
You've got to let go
of this place.
Start a new life.
I can't.
Come with me.
Please!
Wait.
I will not need it
in the promised land.
Never open it
or it will take over your soul.
Always keep it closed.
There you go. Up you go.
There you go. come on.
Let's go. go. come on.
come on. let's hurry.
All of you in the back.
please come to the truck.
Whoa. whoa.
why aren't you on the truck?
This list.
I need to be a part of it.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
Don't talk about that
ever again.
Do you want get us
all thrown in jail?
Listen.
I know these people.
these names on your list.
I know how they think.
I can help you.
So get on that truck.
We need you in Palestina.
- Not here.
- No.
I want my revenge.
I deserve it.
Michael. I deserve this!
Everything you're about to see
is under the radar.
The Brits mustn't know
about a thing.
We have two rules.
One. we never operate when the
kids and families are around.
And two. there always must be
more than one source
of intel on a suspect.
We're from
the British Military Police.
I'm afraid I must ask you
to join us.
Menash.
A burn scar.
It's a war injury.
Same place
as the SS blood group tattoo.
What a coincidence.
You dirty Jew...
We hereby declare you guilty
in taking part and cooperating
in the killings of innocents.
We sentence you to death.
Do you recognize this man?
He was the head
of Block 11 in Majdanek.
Smashed a newborn baby...
Head of the guards of the
Dachau Concentration Camp.
You shot two
Jewish families. hiding in the attic.
SS Guard at the camp
in Bergen-Belsen
Concentration Camp.
In the name
of out brothers and sisters.
We hereby sentence you to death.
- Herr Greiser?
- There's no one here.
Come on.
Let's go.
Probably headed to South America
like the rest of his friends.
We need two sources of intel.
This takes time.
Did you check the barn?
Yeah. Nothing.
That's how they used
to hang people in the camp.
Leave them hanging like this
until they'd fall apart.
Looks like
someone got here first.
"Nakam".
Someone left us a message.
Bruno Langendorf.
do you take responsibility
for your actions?
No one is innocent.
Not me. not you.
Keep digging.
Cigarette?
Max. can I ask you something?
I just want to understand.
There were so many of you
in the ghettos.
in the camps.
And how many people guarded you?
Fifty?
A hundred?
There were thousands of you.
Why didn't you do anything?
All of you.
just walking in one long
straight line to your death.
Why didn't you resist?
You see them take your kids.
your family.
and you just do nothing?
Why didn't you fight back?
Menash. stop it!
Leave him alone.
It's enough.
Go on!
Do it!
No! Stop it. no!
Max. no. stop it. no. not him.
Yes. him!
Go. go. go. go.
He's over there.
On the left side.
On the right.
on the right. Where did he go?
Menash?
Where did he go? Where is he?
Nothing here.
Max!
You can come out of the woods.
The war is over. you know?
Is it really over?
No. no. no.
Can I have my gun back. please?
This is wrong!
We will not hurt civilians.
Where is your humanity?
Who are these people?
Jewish Revengers.
Led by Abba Kovner.
They call themselves Nakam.
The biblical word
for "vengeance".
Dark. dangerous.
Not like our revenge.
Our brothers...
we might share the same rage
but not the same path.
I wish you could stand with us.
I just hope
you won't stand against us.
Let's go.
These people are trouble.
Well. we can't go back
looking like this.
Come in.
I will die.
This is ice water.
What?
I'm a desert man.
No! Stop. stop.
Get inside the water. come on!
No. it's cold.
Hey. you all right?
Yes. sure.
Good.
Thank you.
for letting me be part of this.
I didn't tell them yet
but the Brits know.
They know that ex Nazis are
disappearing around this area.
So they're sending us all
to Belgium.
The whole brigade.
But what about the list?
This is just a drop
in a bucket. Max.
We'll never get them all.
So are the
mountains of Jerusalem
anything like this?
Well. they're smaller.
but far more beautiful.
And it's
the only safe place we have.
So that's it?
Well. for them. it is.
I was drafted to the Haganah.
It's the military organization
back home.
The leadership
wants me to stay behind
and take care
of all kinds of problems.
Like Abba and his group?
For them everyone
in Germany is guilty.
It's not just about
killing war criminals.
it's about killing
German civilians too.
I can help you. Michael.
These kind of people.
they have been through hell.
They will trust no one.
But they might trust me.
They're planning something big
in Nuremberg.
we just don't know
what it is yet.
And we are in a critical state.
The world is in chaos.
but there is a historical
opportunity here.
The world might give us a land.
a country of our own.
A safe place where Jews
will not be hunted
and persecuted anymore.
Go ahead.
You're part of the Haganah now.
I'll see you in Nuremberg.
Wait. no!
No!
Who are you?
- Why are you following us?
- No. wait.
- Who are you working for?
- I know him.
He's with the Jewish Brigade.
They sent him to spy on us.
No one sent me.
I'm not a soldier!
Look!
Yes. I am sorry.
but you cannot be here.
- No. Wait. wait!
- Release him.
Release him.
Why did you leave the Brigade?
They moved on. I just can't.
Please. please take a look.
This is a list of SS officers.
here.
please take a look.
You are the one
that Anna saved in the woods.
Yeah.
Is there
anything you're good at?
I can draw.
I was an art student once too.
In another lifetime.
I'm afraid you'll have to leave.
Please. I have
nowhere else to go.
Well. you can spend
the night here.
Thank you.
But you'll have to leave
by morning.
Anyone
incapable of hard physical labor
should leave now.
Priority will be given
to men and women
experienced in water plant work.
Anyone
incapable of hard physical labor
should leave now.
Priority will be given
to men and women...
Get out of my way.
let me through.
Stay back. stay back.
Wait.
No. sorry.
Next. ID?
Baumann. Paul?
Yes.
Previous experience?
Plumber.
Do you have
any other certificate?
I'm a hydraulic engineer.
I worked as a plumber
before the war.
You're lying.
- No. No. no. listen.
- Next. Next.
Give me a chance to explain.
- Step back for a second.
- I'm calling the guards!
I spent the last five years
in service of the Reich.
protecting our race.
keeping it pure.
They might hang me.
I need this job.
Please.
Thank you.
Next.
Who is this man?
What are you doing here?
He is placed
in the filtration center.
With access to the main well.
You trust him?
Let him work.
All new recruits follow me.
Come on. move along.
I'm Willi.
Paul.
Oh. I missed working!
Finally. we can go
back to normal. right?
The water supply of the city
needs to be rebuilt
as fast as possible
to provide clean running water
for the city again.
To bring water
back to our great nation.
Come on. faster. come along.
As you can see all over.
we really need your hard work.
Here. you're looking
at the main turbine
of the filtration center.
The heart of the city.
Once we repair it.
this heart
will start beating again.
20.000 cubic meters of water
will flow through
here every hour.
Here. we infiltrate the chlorine
to purify the water
from bacteria.
And from here.
it flows to the entire city.
- I am in.
- Good.
Very good.
What? What is it?
This is much bigger
than you thought. Michael.
- What are you talking about?
- Much bigger.
Abba has his people everywhere.
They're spreading all over
Germany. forming other cells.
In Hamburg. in Cologne. Munich.
in Berlin and here in Nuremberg.
This revenge is painted
on a much bigger canvas.
This is madness.
But for them. it's justice.
I need you to find
more information.
Gain Abba's trust.
He's the key.
If we won't stop them.
if they succeed
in their devilish plan.
everything will change.
Everything.
The world
will look at us differently
and we won't get our country.
Do you understand that?
Max. look at me.
I trust you.
I know.
The nights
are always the hardest.
Nothing to keep the demons away.
What are you writing?
"My brothers in ruin.
Gaping hollow of my landscape.
The guilt is not yours.
At your doorway.
the appointed hour rang.
Your day. unimagined.
For you chose nothing and in
nothing. nothing did you sin."
We were the first ones
that people saw
when they arrived at the camp.
Families.
children.
When I helped them off the
train. I would smile at them.
My work was to collect
their suitcases...
write their names down.
I told them I would bring
it back after they shower.
That way...
they walked calmly.
After they went in. I would
go through their luggage.
take any food I could find.
We had food.
That's why they called us
the "Canada" crew.
As if our lives were rich
and relaxed.
I had to lie to them
to give them hope.
Even though
I knew there was none.
Ever since.
there's not a single day...
not one moment.
where I don't ask myself
why didn't I do anything
or why...
why didn't I warn them.
tell them to run.
something. anything?
Never again will we go
like sheep to the slaughter.
It is our time to make sure
that the rest of the world
learns the same lesson.
I can help.
Good night. Max.
You trust him?
He shares our pain.
Never again.
We all fled the ghetto
at the last minute.
We had to leave
our families behind.
We ran off to the woods.
At night we fought.
During the days.
we made plans for our revenge.
Abba came up with plan A.
We will not wait for the courts
to do their so-called justice.
Look at them.
They saw us
expelled from schools...
from our businesses.
from our homes...
they cheered.
They knew about the death camps.
These people are not victims.
They heard our screams.
They murdered our children...
and then went home to read
bedtime stories to their own.
It's said that they're going
to put some of them on trial.
here in the city.
But the way we see it.
the whole German nation
should be on the stand.
Thousand years of pain
in our veins.
Never again.
An eye for an eye.
Six million for six million.
Four years of service.
I ate this shit in a can.
And now the war is over
and look at me.
Still eating this pile of shit.
Where were you stationed?
They sent me to the East Front.
To fight against the Russians.
What about you?
Where were you stationed?
Auschwitz Birkenau.
Goddamn Hitler.
The maps we have now
are useless.
I know.
I tried.
but he's standing there.
never takes his eyes off them.
I win. should we go again?
Hey. Paul!
Easy there.
Hey. hey. easy!
Come on. come on. stand up.
Come on. stand up.
Yeah. come on. come on.
come on. come on.
Help me a little bit.
yeah. that's good.
Okay. What's going on. eh?
Okay. here.
bend down. bend down.
Yeah. that's good. come on.
come on. on your feet.
On your feet.
Here. it's tea.
It has a lot of sugar in it
and you need the energy.
Come on.
Oh. yeah.
I make this schnapps myself.
Better than tea. huh.
don't you think?
Oh. sir!
What going on?
The poor guy
almost died in my hands.
Take 10 more minutes to rest.
Willi.
Yeah.
Thank you.
We need to fix the west pipe.
Take five men and go down there.
Hey. Paul. you feel better?
Yes. I'm fine.
What are you doing over there?
A tree.
Look. it's the foreman's map.
And this is north.
These are the main lines.
So if we pour the poison
right here.
we won't be able to backtrack
out because this area is guarded.
Maybe we take a closer look
at this area down the line.
this might be
our only escape route.
Here.
Do you really think
that we can kill millions of
people and get out of it alive?
If the allies won't kill us.
the Haganah will.
When will the turbine
start functioning?
The progress is slow.
Same for the main pipes.
It all must be ready
before Abba returns.
From where?
Where is Abba now?
He is heading to Palestina.
He wasn't able
to get the poison in Europe.
Our people there will help him.
Belkin.
It's Shabat.
Not for me.
Not anymore.
The dreams are getting blurry.
So I have to draw them.
Draw for me.
Draw my son.
My Menachem.
He was seven years old.
He had curly hair.
big dark eyes.
rosy cheeks.
He was kind.
Had a very big heart.
He loved listening to music...
and my bedtime stories.
Mentally.
he was strong. stubborn.
But physically. he wasn't.
We fled the ghetto
through the sewer tunnels.
Crawling for hours in darkness.
It was too much for him.
He couldn't breathe.
It was raining that night
and the water level was higher
than we expected.
I tried...
He was so weak.
Do you think the pain
will ever go away?
I hope not.
Go away.
They're starting to come back.
Who?
Jews.
They think they can take
everything back now.
Hey!
Leave them alone!
We have to help them!
It will draw too much attention.
Be patient. they will all get
what they deserve.
Come on. let's hurry.
we're already late.
You all worked hard and we
still have a lot of work to do.
but today. when you go home
to your loved ones.
you all can be proud.
From now on. running water
will reach every household.
Come on.
The heart of the city
is alive again!
Let the water flow.
Anna?
Come.
The last time I went
to see a movie
was years ago with my parents.
She's so beautiful.
Then denials
of surrender is on its way.
Then the news hits Times Square.
New York and main streets
everywhere.
pulls out the stop
and let's celebrate.
Yet from coast to coast.
victory gets
a spontaneous welcome.
The kissing.
the impromptu entertainment.
the biggest noisiest
celebration in New York's history.
Two days of this going on
before we face the realities
of peace in a world which
contains a new cosmic force.
the atomic bomb.
During the war.
the Nazis maintained
some 250 concentration camps
and exterminated an estimated
10 million civilians
and prisoners of war.
Various methods of killing
were used.
- No. We need to see this.
- The favorite for the Nazis
was extermination
in the gas chambers.
More than five million prisoners
were killed
in this convenient manner.
usually after starvation
and torturing.
But poison gas
did not inflict enough pain
for the more bloodthirsty Nazis.
Other prisoners were poisoned.
shot or subjected
to bacteriologic experiments.
Anna. look at it. Look at it.
At some camps.
prisoners were burned alive.
their ashes
made into fertilizers
and their bones
sold to the makers of soap.
The Nazi Concentration Camp
guards
killed some three million
human beings in one camp alone.
Camp doctors radically admitted
that they had performed
sadistic experiments
on hundreds of thousands
of prisoners.
Anna.
It's an honor to meet you.
Mr. Kovner.
We heard about your arrival.
How may we help you?
I'm looking for a substance.
Something very powerful.
something that has no taste.
and no smell.
and leaves no trace behind.
We are running out of time.
When will they attack?
I don't know.
They keep on coming in.
Americans. Brits.
Russians. French.
all grabbing a piece of Germany.
Dividing it
as if it was a birthday cake.
My friends back home
are losing their patience.
And I can't hold them back
much longer.
We need to stop these people.
Now.
Where is he?
I don't know!
They don't trust me yet!
That's strange.
You seem to be quite close
to the woman. Anna?
You know. Germany is not
a safe place for Jews.
It will be a shame
if something terrible happens.
The allies.
There are more and more forces
coming into town.
- We need...
- We know.
Sit down.
It's from Palestina.
The wedding is delayed.
Abba was supposed to get
the poison in one month.
It's been three.
This letter was sent weeks ago.
Maybe he got the poison already.
Or maybe
he's just dead somewhere.
It's taking too long.
And I'm sure the other cells
are thinking the same.
We have to be patient.
There are too many
American soldiers.
What are you saying?
She's saying it's too late.
Well. it's too late to stop now!
The Americans are everywhere.
we can not poison our allies.
This is war.
We always knew
there would be casualties.
"He who passed
over the houses...
of the children of Israel.
when he struck down Egypt."
We'll have to block the pipes
to the allied quarters.
We have to go down
to the tunnels.
Menach!
Shh. shh. shh.
We'll meet back here
in one hour.
Anna!
Anna. Anna!
Are you all right?
- Are you all right?
- I can't breathe.
Come on. Follow me.
I can't breathe.
Yes. you can breathe.
You are fine. breathe.
Deep breaths.
He is too heavy.
He's too heavy.
I cannot hold him.
Please help me.
I can not hold him.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry. Menachem.
Anna. listen to me.
It's not your fault.
There is nothing
you could have done.
Did you hear that?
We have to go.
Is anyone there?
Come with me. we have to go.
- Max.
- Tzvi. help me.
Hold on to me. come on.
What's with her?
She is fine.
Too much to drink.
What's the story
with you people?
What are you doing in there.
always locked in your attic?
Can you please let us pass?
I could swear I heard
Jewish prayers the other day.
Let's go. Let's go.
- Don't touch me.
- I'm sorry.
I knew it!
You are Jews!
I knew it! They are Jews.
What's that?
Abba.
Did you?
No. I couldn't.
I was waiting for you.
Well?
Open up.
- What does it say?
- Open the door.
What's going on?
These are not the neighbors.
It's the Haganah.
Open the door.
Go. go. go.
Where is he?
You might as well shoot us.
No!
Hold on!
I'll tell you.
We have a message here.
A letter from Abba.
Max.
Here.
He's in Palestina.
Read.
This time I'm going to kill you.
He was trying to get the
poison. but with no success.
No one is willing to help him.
It is over.
I'm sorry. Tzvi.
What you're trying to do
would not stop the hatred.
It will only make it stronger.
We'll never be safe here.
And right now. far from here.
people are working
in the fields.
planting trees. building houses.
People are starting families.
having children.
a whole new generation
that knows no fear!
That's the real revenge.
As I see it.
you have two options.
It's either I'm handing you
over to my friends here.
or by tomorrow...
you will all leave this city.
What's it gonna be?
What is this?
This is the letter from Abba.
I gave him the old one.
"Sweetheart. my beloved uncle
gave me the money.
I was able to get
the medication.
I'm on my way back to you.
my love.
Our glorious wedding
will take place as planned."
Now what?
Anna?
You and Belkin have a long way.
You should take the train.
head to the port to meet Abba.
I'll send a telegram
to the other cells.
they need to prepare.
Max. you need to stay here.
in case Abba arrives sooner.
This is it.
We're about to change history.
Let's finish this.
Yes.
Anna?
What are you doing?
Anna.
Abba is coming soon.
The water is running.
Everything is ready.
I'm not.
I'm leaving.
Where?
Where we belong.
Anna. what about Menachem?
You owe him justice!
I can not do this.
Killing children.
No more deaths.
Come with me.
Where are the others?
Tzvi and Belkin went to get you.
Anna... she left.
Do you have it?
The city hall has been rebuilt
and restored.
We're happy
to announce the city hall...
We're being followed.
We need to split up.
Give me the bag.
I know what to do.
- Are you sure?
- Give me the bag.
Good luck. Max.
Now!
Max!
Max. stop!
Stop!
Drop it.
Give me the poison. Max.
Max. look at me. it's all right.
Give me the poison.
No. no. no!
Not a day goes by
when I don't think
about what would have happened
if plan A had been carried out.
I often think about the poison
flowing through the veins
of Germany.
Help me stop this.
Illegal passenger
on board. arrest him immediately.
The British police
stopped the ship
just a few miles off the coast.
They were looking for Abba.
Hey. hey!
Stop!
The cells in the other cities
broke apart once they
understood Abba wasn't coming.
As for me.
I decided to go home...
to have a good life.
That was my revenge.
What if I told you
that your family was murdered.
Just imagine for a minute.
Your brothers. sisters...
parents...
your kids...
everyone...
murdered.
For no reason at all.
Now ask yourself...
what would you do?